Guide to the Millicent Todd Bingham Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Emily Dickinson, 1828-(1894-1956)-1969; Series V; 16 linear feet (39 boxes)
  - Scrapbooks
    - "Letters of E.D., New and enlarged edition; E.D. Face to Face, 1931-1934 (Box 109, Folder 673)
    - " Bolts of Melody; Ancestors' Brocades Articles, plays about E.D.", 1943-1949 (Box 110, Folder 674)
    - Emily Dickinson, A Revelation; Emily Dickinson's Home; The Poems of E.D. (Johnson); E.D.'s letters to the Hollands" with fragments of ms drafts, 1950-1957 (Box 111, Folder 675)
    - "Gift of Dickinson papers to Amherst College; Articles about E.D.", 1956-1958 (Box 112, Folder 676)
    - Reviews of first E.D. books (unbound), 1890-1895 (Box 112, Folder 677-678)
    - Reviews of MTB books (unbound)
      - 1931-1932, 1945 (Box 112, Folder 679-681)
      - 1951-1955, 1967 (Box 113, Folder 682)
    - Articles re: donation of ED papers (unbound), Circa 1956 (Box 113, Folder 684)
    - Reviews of Martha Dickinson Bianchi books (unbound) (Box 113, Folder 685)
    - Reviews of Thomas H. Johnson books (unbound) (Box 113, Folder 686)
    - Reviews of Jay Leyda books (unbound) (Box 113, Folder 687)
    - Reviews of books by Genevieve Taggard, Charles R. Anderson and Theodora Ward (unbound) (Box 113, Folder 688)
    - Magazine articles (unbound) (Box 113, Folder 689)
    - Miscellaneous articles (unbound) (Box 113, Folder 690-694)
    - Programs (unbound), 1930-1966 (Box 113, Folder 695)
  - Articles by Others
    - 1891-1971 (Box 114, Folder 696-703)
    - "Emily Dickinson Bulletin", 1968-1969 (Box 114, Folder 704)
    - "Emily Dickinson Bulletin" (MTB memorial issue), 1969 September (Box 114, Folder 705)
    - no date (Box 114, Folder 706)
- Conservation, 1865 -1968; Series VI; 5 linear feet (12 boxes)
  Correspondence is arranged chronologically. Writings is organized by author, and filed chronologically under each name. The other sections are arranged by subject and type of material.
  - Correspondence
    - 1903-1939 (Box 115, Folder 1-19)
    - 1940-1954 (Box 116, Folder 20-43)
    - 1955-1965 (Box 117, Folder 44-64)
    - 1966-1968, no date (Box 118, Folder 65-70)
  - Writings
    - Millicent Todd Bingham
      - "The Todd Wild Life Sanctuary", 1935 (Box 118, Folder 71-72)
      - "Rescuing an Island", 1937 (Box 118, Folder 73-74)
      - "Towards Conservation", 1937 (Box 118, Folder 75)
      - "A Geographer Looks at the Yosemite", 1948 (Box 118, Folder 76)
      - Review of Paul Sears, Charles Darwin, 1950 (Box 118, Folder 77)
      - "Beyond Psychology", 1952 (Box 118, Folder 78)
      - Homo Sapiens Auduboniensis, a Tribute to Walter VanDyke Bingham, 1953 (Box 118, Folder 79-80)
      - Homo Sapiens Auduboniensis, 1953 (Box 119, Folder 81-82)
      - John and Elizabeth Baker anniversary tribute, 1961 (Box 119, Folder 83)
      - The Mabel Loomis Todd Forest, presentation remarks, 1961 (Box 119, Folder 84)
      - Taped interviews: typewritten transcripts, 1963, 1965 (Box 119, Folder 85-86)
      - Notes for book on Hog Island, 1965 (Box 119, Folder 87)
      - Miscellaneous notes and jottings, undated (Box 119, Folder 88)
    - Walter VanDyke Bingham: "... Homo Sapiens Auduboniensis"; "A Primitive Psychological Experiment", 1937, undated (Box 119, Folder 89)
    - Mabel Loomis Todd
      - "Epic of Hog", Circa 1931 (Box 119, Folder 90)
      - "Muscongus Island, Maine", 1931 (Box 119, Folder 91-92)
    - Eben Jenks Loomis: miscellaneous, manuscripts (gathered by MTB for use in Hog Island book), undated (Box 119, Folder 93-94)
  - Hog Island and Maine
    - Maps of Hog Island (Box 120, Folder 95)
    - Notebook by MTB, 1935-1949 (Box 120, Folder 96)
    - Articles and historical notes by MTB (Box 120, Folder 97)
    - Notes and jottings by MTB, 1911-1965, undated (Box 120, Folder 98-100)
    - Notes and jottings by Walter VanDyke Bingham (Box 120, Folder 101)
    - Notes and jottings by Mabel Loomis Todd (Box 120, Folder 102)
    - Legal documents
      - Deeds to Hog Island, 1865-1909 (Box 120, Folder 103)
      - Mortgages, deeds, abstract of title, 1908-1935 (Box 120, Folder 104)
      - Appraisals, miscellaneous papers, 1953-1958 (Box 120, Folder 105)
    - Financial documents
      - Bills, 1911-1964 (Box 120, Folder 106)
      - Insurance policies, 1918-1957 (Box 120, Folder 107)
    - Scientific research on Hog Island: proposals, reports, and notes, Circa 1960-1965 (Box 120, Folder 108)
    - "Takusan"
      - Ship's logs, 1915-1927, 1941 (Box 121, Folder 109-110)
      - Correspondence, 1930-1945 (Box 121, Folder 111)
      - Notes and jottings, undated (Box 121, Folder 112)
      - Financial and legal documents, 1913-1939 (Box 121, Folder 113)
    - Maine history, manuscripts by A. K. Little, 1946-1954, undated (Box 121, Folder 114)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts about Maine, undated (Box 121, Folder 115)
    - Articles about Maine (Box 121, Folder 116)
    - Pamphlets and brochures about Maine (Box 121, Folder 117-119)
    - Pamphlets and brochures: church and civic material (Box 122, Folder 120)
    - Printed matter: commercial and miscellaneous (Box 122, Folder 121)
    - Maps of Maine (Box 122, Folder 122)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1909-1967 (Box 122, Folder 123)
  - Audubon Nature Camp
    - MTB's speeches to campers, 1936-1968 (Box 122, Folder 124-126)
      See also: items 2-5 in appendix
    - MTB's "Report for the Season of 1938" (Box 122, Folder 127)
    - Notes and jottings by MTB, 1933-1968 (Box 122, Folder 128)
    - National Audubon Society press releases, 1935-1968 (Box 122, Folder 129)
    - Camp papers
      - Enrollment figures, instructional materials, activities, 1936-1968 (Box 122, Folder 130)
      - Reports, speeches, poems, 1938-1958, undated (Box 122, Folder 131)
      - Reunion menus, invitations, place cards, 1936-1955, undated (Box 122, Folder 132)
    - Lists of campers and staff, 1936-1948 (Box 122, Folder 133)
    - Lists of campers and staff, 1949-1968 (Box 123, Folder 134-136)
    - Legal documents
      - Leases, right-of-way, 1935 (Box 123, Folder 137)
      - Leases, deeds, 1948-1958 (Box 123, Folder 138)
    - Camp brochures, 1936-1968 (Box 123, Folder 139)
    - Articles about the camp, 1935-1960 (Box 123, Folder 140-142)
    - News clippings about the camp
      - 1932-1960 (Box 123, Folder 143-144)
      - 1962-1968 (Box 124, Folder 145)
    - Donation of Todd Wildlife Sanctuary
      - Drafts of precatory letter, 1958-1960 (Box 124, Folder 146)
      - Lists of guests, 1960 (Box 124, Folder 147)
      - Invitations, programs, National Audubon Society resolution, 1960 (Box 124, Folder 148)
      - Speeches and articles (TMs), 1960 (Box 124, Folder 149)
      - Printed articles, 1936, 1938, 1960 (Box 124, Folder 150)
    - Memorabilia and miscellaneous papers, 1938, undated (Box 124, Folder 151)
  - Mabel Loomis Todd Forest (Pelham Knob)
    - Presentation ceremony: speeches, precatory letter, 1961 (Box 124, Folder 152)
    - Presentation ceremony: invitations, programs, booklet, guest list, 1961 (Box 124, Folder 153)
    - Notes on the Knob as a preserve, 1908-1948, undated (Box 124, Folder 154)
    - Deeds, tax bills, surveys, 1909-1961 (Box 124, Folder 155)
    - Clippings about the Forest (Box 124, Folder 156)
    - Reference materials (Box 124, Folder 157-158)
  - General Conservation
    - National Audubon Society (Box 124, Folder 159-160)
    - Audubon Society of the District of Columbia (Box 124, Folder 161-162)
    - Audubon Societies: Canada, Florida, Maine, Rhode Island (Box 125, Folder 163)
    - Audubon Society of Massachusetts (Box 125, Folder 164)
    - United States Department of the Interior (Box 125, Folder 165)
    - Forestry pamphlets (Box 125, Folder 166)
    - Parks and sanctuaries (Box 125, Folder 167-168)
    - Manuscripts (Box 125, Folder 169)
    - Articles, 1930-1966 (Box 125, Folder 170-172)
    - Booklets (Box 125, Folder 173)
    - Pamphlets, brochures, catalogues, advertisements (Box 125, Folder 174)
    - Periodicals and clippings, 1916-1968 (Box 126, Folder 175-176)
    - Printed matter (Box 126, Folder 177)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1892-1968 (Box 126, Folder 178-180)
- Diaries, Notebooks and Scrapbooks, 1882-1968; Series VII; 11 linear feet (27 Boxes)
  The series is organized by the form of the material. Each part of the series (e.g., Journals [bound]), is arranged chronologically.
  - Journals (bound)
    - Europe, 1899 (Box 127, Folder 1)
    - Southeast Asia, 1901 (Box 127, Folder 2-4)
    - Paris, 1905 (Box 127, Folder 5-6)
    - Paris, 1906 (Box 128, Folder 7)
    - Germany, 1906 (Box 128, Folder 8)
    - South America (with typed transcript), 1907 (Box 128, Folder 9-10)
    - Berlin, 1909-1910 (Box 128, Folder 11-12)
    - Russia, 1914 (Box 128, Folder 13)
    - Russia (typed transcript), 1914 (Box 129, Folder 14)
    - Amherst, 1915-1918 (Box 129, Folder 15-16)
    - Paris, Amherst, 1918-1920 (Box 129, Folder 17)
    - 1921 Jan-1922 Feb (Box 129, Folder 18)
    - Paris, Geneva, Berlin, London, Cambridge (with typed transcript), 1927-1928 (Box 129, Folder 19)
    - New York (with typed transcript), 1928 November 3 (Box 129, Folder 20)
    - Gaspé Peninsula (with typed transcript), 1930 (Box 130, Folder 21)
    - Ireland (with typed transcript), 1934 (Box 130, Folder 22-23)
    - New Mexico (with typed transcript), 1938 (Box 130, Folder 24)
    - Amherst, 1940 (Box 130, Folder 25)
    - England, Norway, Salem (with typed transcript), 1951 (Box 130, Folder 26)
    - 1960 Nov-1963 Feb (Box 130, Folder 27)
    - 1963 Mar-1967 Sep (with typed transcript) (Box 130, Folder 28)
  - Journals (unbound)
    - 1895-1914 Aug (Box 130, Folder 29)
    - 1915 Jan-1952 Nov (Box 131, Folder 30-38)
    - 1954 Jan-1967 Sep (Box 132, Folder 39-40)
  - "Baby journal", 1885 (Box 132, Folder 41)
  - Diaries
    - 1888-1899 (Box 132, Folder 42-45)
    - 1900-1909 (Box 133, Folder 46-50)
    - 1910-1917 (Box 134, Folder 51-54)
    - 1918-1925 (Box 135, Folder 55-58)
    - 1926-1931 (Box 136, Folder 59-61)
    - 1932-1937 (Box 137, Folder 62-64)
    - 1938-1943 (Box 138, Folder 65-67)
    - 1944-1951 (Box 139, Folder 68-71)
    - 1952-1959 (Box 140, Folder 72-75)
    - 1960-1967 (Box 141, Folder 76-79)
    - 1968 (Box 142, Folder 80)
    - Loose notes, 1902-1967, undated (Box 142, Folder 81-82)
  - Engagement calendars
    - 1943-1957 (Box 142, Folder 83-87)
    - 1958-1968 (Box 143, Folder 88-91)
  - Memorandum books, 1924-1952 (Box 143, Folder 92-94)
  - Notebooks
    - Temperature readings, 1890-1892 (Box 143, Folder 95)
    - Chicago, 1890-1993 (Box 144, Folder 96)
    - Recipes; candy book, 1893, undated (Box 144, Folder 97)
    - 1899-1911 (Box 144, Folder 98)
    - 1901 (Box 144, Folder 99)
    - Joke book, 1902 (Box 144, Folder 99)
    - 1902 (Box 144, Folder 100)
    - Paris, 1905 (Box 144, Folder 100)
    - 1907 (Box 144, Folder 100)
    - Expenses, 1913-1914 (Box 144, Folder 101)
    - Books read, 1909-1916 (Box 144, Folder 102)
    - Note pad, 1917
    - c. 1919-1920 (Box 145, Folder 103)
    - 1961 (Box 145, Folder 104)
    - 1967, no date (Box 145, Folder 105)
    - Unfinished poetry sampler with flower drawings, undated (Box 145, Folder 106)
    - Note pad: France (Box 145, Folder 107)
    - no date (Box 145, Folder 107)
  - Autograph book, 1887-1895 (Box 145, Folder 108)
  - Guest books
    - Hog Island, 1906-1941 (Box 145, Folder 108)
    - Hog Island, 1938-1967 (Box 145, Folder 109)
    - 1921-1968 (Box 146, Folder 110-111)
  - Address books, Circa 1890-1929, undated (Box 146, Folder 112-115)
  - Scrapbooks
    - "First scrapbook", 1882-1889 (Box 147, Folder 116)
    - Personal, 1897-1899 (Box 147, Folder 117)
    - Tripoli, Paris, 1905-1906 (Box 147, Folder 118)
    - Personal, 1890-1897 (Box 148, Folder 119)
    - Personal, 1897-1899 (Box 149, Folder 120)
    - Vassar, 1899-1900 (Box 150, Folder 121)
    - Personal, 1902-1905 (Box 151, Folder 122)
    - Tripoli, Paris (additional material), 1905-1906 (Box 152, Folder 123)
    - Press notices and reviews, 1908-1926 (Box 152, Folder 124-125)
    - Wedding, 1920 December (Box 152, Folder 126)
    - Wedding, 1920 December (Box 153, Folder 127)
- Personal Papers, 1874-1968; Series VIII; 10 linear feet (23 boxes)
  Writings is arranged chronologically. Persons and Clubs and Organizations are arranged alphabetically by name. Subject Files is organized by subject in roughly chronological order.
  - Writings
    - Correspondence with publishers, agents and book dealers, 1902-1968 (Box 154, Folder 1)
    - The Triangle
      - Printed copies, 1891-1892 (Box 154, Folder 2)
      - Manuscripts, 1891-1892 (Box 154, Folder 3)
    - "A Forest Shadow": printed copy The Vassar Miscellany, 1901 April (Box 154, Folder 4)
    - "The Negritos of the Philippines": printed copy The Vassar Miscellany, 1901 (Box 154, Folder 5)
    - "Aunt Eliza Thompson" AMs, 1902 (Box 154, Folder 6)
    - The Life of Mary E. Stearns, 1909
      - Extra-illustrated edition
        - Volume I (Box 154, Folder 7)
        - Volume II (Box 155, Folder 8)
        - Illustration plans and photographs (Box 155, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence with Houghton Mifflin Company, 1907-1911 (Box 155, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence, 1906-1964, undated (Box 155, Folder 11-16)
      - Notes (Box 156, Folder 17)
      - Subscriptions and advertisements (Box 156, Folder 18)
      - Newspaper clippings and reviews (Box 156, Folder 19)
      - "Mrs. W. F. Stearns Memorial Fund"" correspondence, 1905-1909 (Box 156, Folder 20)
    - Eben Jenks Loomis, 1913
      - Printed copy (Box 156, Folder 21)
      - List of people who attended reading (Box 156, Folder 22)
      - Correspondence and financial papers, Houghton Mifflin Co., 1913 (Box 156, Folder 23)
      - Correspondence, 1913-1914 (Box 156, Folder 24-25)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1913 (Box 156, Folder 26)
    - "The Amherst Eclipse Expedition to Russia" ( The Nation ), 1914 October 8 (Box 156, Folder 27)
    - "Adrift in Russia", 1915
      - TMs (Box 156, Folder 28)
      - Drafts, AMs and TMs, 1915 (Box 156, Folder 29)
      - Correspondence, 1915-1922 (Box 156, Folder 30)
    - "The Cult of Kiev" ( Vassar Quarterly ): TMs and draft, 1916 February (Box 156, Folder 31)
    - "The Cult of Kiev": notes and clippings, 1916 (Box 156, Folder 32)
    - "What is the Matter with the Weather?" ( Boston American ): TMs, 1916 July 30 (Box 156, Folder 33)
    - World War I journals: TMs, 1914-1918 (Box 156, Folder 34)
    - Letters from France
      - 1918 April-June 1918 April-June (Box 156, Folder 35)
      - Typed excerpts, 1918 July-1919 July (Box 157, Folder 36-40)
    - "Solar Eclipse Photography": printed copy ( Popular Astronomy ), TMs, notes, 1923 December (Box 157, Folder 41)
    - "Solar Eclipse Photography": correspondence, 1923 (Box 157, Folder 42)
    - "Florence Cushing at Homewood": printed copy ( Vassar Quarterly ), TMs, 1928 March (Box 157, Folder 43)
    - "Solar Eclipses" (letter to Science magazine): correspondence, 1929 June 21 (Box 157, Folder 44)
    - "A Friend of Amherst [Mabel Loomis Todd]" ( The Amherst Record ): printed copies, 1932 November 9 (Box 157, Folder 45)
    - "Scientific and Literary Achievements of the Todd Family": TMs and clippings, 1933 January 23 (Box 157, Folder 46)
    - Mabel Loomis Todd, Her Contributions to the Town of Amherst, 1935
      - Printed copies (Box 157, Folder 47)
      - TMs (Box 157, Folder 48)
      - Correspondence with George Grady Press, Inc., 1935-1959 (Box 157, Folder 49)
      - Correspondence, 1933-1959 (Box 157, Folder 50)
      - Newspaper clippings, invitation, 1935 (Box 157, Folder 51)
    - "Training of the Mind": TMs, 1939(?) (Box 157, Folder 52)
    - "Shelling in Sanibel": TMs, 1940 (Box 157, Folder 53)
    - "Chasing Eclipses: the Making of a Geographer": outline, notes, correspondence and clippings, 1941 (Box 157, Folder 54)
    - Radio interview, WWDC, Washington, D.C.; TMs and correspondence, 1941 August (Box 157, Folder 55)
    - Review of "Remembrance of Amherst" ( American Historical Review ): TMs and correspondence, 1946 October (Box 157, Folder 56)
    - Review of An Amherst Boyhood: TMs, 1946 (Box 157, Folder 57)
    - "The New England Way": TMs, correspondence and notes, 1949 April (Box 157, Folder 58)
    - "The Last Days of Eleonora Duse", 1954
      - TMs (Box 157, Folder 59)
      - TMs draft (Box 158, Folder 60)
      - Correspondence, notes and newspaper clippings, 1949-1956 (Box 158, Folder 61)
    - "Birth of an Anthem": TMs, correspondence and notes, 1956 (Box 158, Folder 62)
    - "Accident Prone" ( Notes and Queries ), TMs and correspondence, 1959 (Box 158, Folder 63)
    - "Southeast Asia at the Turn of the Century", 1960
      - TMs, 1960 January (Box 158, Folder 64)
      - TMs and notes, 1961 February (Box 158, Folder 65)
    - Walter VanDyke Bingham Bibliography, 1962 March
      - Printed copy and notes (Box 158, Folder 66)
      - Correspondence, 1961 October-1964 May (Box 158, Folder 67)
    - "Presentation of the Galileo Portrait to Amherst College": TMs, correspondence and publicity, 1962 June 10 (Box 158, Folder 68)
    - "Russia-Summer of 1914"
      - TMs, 1964 December 5 (Box 158, Folder 69)
      - Notes and invitations, 1964 December 5 (Box 158, Folder 70)
    - "Key West in the Summer of 1864" ( The Florida Historical Quarterly ): printed copy, TMs, correspondence and notes, 1965 January (Box 158, Folder 71)
    - "Presentation of Citations" ( American Psychologist ), TMs, 1965 September (Box 158, Folder 72)
    - Speeches: correspondence, clippings, and publicity, 1904-1953 (Box 158, Folder 73)
    - Notes for lectures, 1914-1930 (Box 158, Folder 74)
    - Notes on folklore: notes, clippings and articles, Undated (Box 158, Folder 75)
    - Notes, Undated (Box 158, Folder 76-77)
  - Persons
    - Agard, Walter (Box 159, Folder 78)
    - Anderson, Harriet (Box 159, Folder 79)
    - Aschenbach, Marion (Loomis) (Box 159, Folder 80)
    - Askling, John (Box 159, Folder 81)
    - Besnard, Paul Albert (Box 159, Folder 82)
    - Bingham, Hiram (Box 159, Folder 83)
    - Bingham, Mary (Box 159, Folder 84)
    - Bingham, Walter VanDyke
      - Bibliography of his writings, 1962 (Box 159, Folder 85)
      - Correspondence on writing his biography, 1964-1967 (Box 159, Folder 86)
      - Records of final illness, 1951-1952 (Box 159, Folder 87)
      - Burial at Arlington Cemetary, 1952 (Box 159, Folder 88)
      - Letters of condolence to MTB on death of WVB
        - 1952-1954 1952-1954 (Box 159, Folder 89-95)
        - 1952-1954 1952-1954 (Box 160, Folder 96-98)
      - Cards from flowers received on death of WVB, 1952 July (Box 160, Folder 99)
      - Correspondence and notes on the disposition of WVB's papers, 1951-1968 (Box 160, Folder 100-101)
    - Bingham, Walter VanDyke, Memorial Lectures
      - 1952-1960 1952-1960 (Box 160, Folder 102-109)
      - 1961-1968 1961-1968 (Box 161, Folder 110-119)
    - Blanchard, Prof. Raoul (Box 161, Folder 120)
    - Bode, Helen (Box 161, Folder 121)
    - Boyd, Louise A. (Box 161, Folder 122)
    - Bronk, Detlev W. (Box 161, Folder 123)
    - Bucheister, Carl (Box 161, Folder 124)
    - ________, Harriet (Box 161, Folder 124)
    - Cadbury, Bartram (Box 161, Folder 125)
    - Carson, Rachel L. (Box 161, Folder 126)
    - Clark, John M. (Box 161, Folder 127)
    - Clarke, James (Box 161, Folder 128)
    - ________, Esther (Box 161, Folder 128)
    - Coburn, Charles (Box 161, Folder 129)
    - Davis, Elmer (Box 162, Folder 130)
    - Duse, Eleonora (Box 162, Folder 131-136)
    - Fairchild, David (Box 162, Folder 137)
    - Ferguson, Leonard W. (Box 162, Folder 138-139)
    - Flanders, Ralph E. (Box 162, Folder 140)
    - ________, Helen (Box 162, Folder 140)
    - Franklin, Ralph (Box 162, Folder 141)
    - Frazier, Lewis R. (Box 162, Folder 142)
    - ________, Charles R. (Box 162, Folder 142)
    - Frost, Robert (Box 162, Folder 143)
    - Fuess, C. M. (Box 162, Folder 144)
    - Gaunt, Merrill S. (Box 162, Folder 145)
    - Grosvenor, Gilbert H. (Box 162, Folder 146)
    - Guber, Prof. Alexander (Box 162, Folder 147)
    - Harper, Roland M. (Box 162, Folder 148)
    - Harris, Mary (Box 162, Folder 149)
    - Hilder, Howard (Box 162, Folder 150)
    - Hoagland, Marjorie (Box 162, Folder 151)
    - Hogue, Richard W. (Box 162, Folder 152)
    - ________, Caroline (Box 162, Folder 152)
    - Hubbard, Elizabeth (Box 162, Folder 153)
    - Hunt, Norman (Box 162, Folder 154)
    - Hunt, Rachel McMasters (Miller) (Box 163, Folder 155)
    - ________, Roy A. (Box 163, Folder 155)
    - Hyde, William DeWitt (Box 163, Folder 156)
    - Ilse, Albert (Box 163, Folder 157)
    - Ivanovsky, Alexandra (Box 163, Folder 158)
    - ________, Catherine (Box 163, Folder 158)
    - ________, Nathaly (Box 163, Folder 158)
    - Jackson, Helen Hunt (Box 163, Folder 159)
    - James, Arthur Curtiss (Box 163, Folder 160-161)
    - James, D. Willis (Box 163, Folder 162)
    - Kent, Mrs. Everett (Box 163, Folder 163)
    - Lancaster, Helen Clark (Box 163, Folder 164)
    - Leland, Waldo Gifford (Box 163, Folder 165)
    - Loomis, Eben Jenks (Box 163, Folder 166-167)
    - ________, Mary Alden (Wilder) (Box 163, Folder 167)
    - Loomis, Harriet C. B. (Box 163, Folder 168)
    - Loomis, Mahlon (Box 163, Folder 169-170)
    - Lowell, Amy
      - Correspondence (Box 163, Folder 171)
      - Walter VanDyke Bingham's notes about the creative process (Box 163, Folder 172)
      - Word association test given by Walter VanDyke Bingham to Amy Lowell, 1924 August 10 (Box 163, Folder 173)
      - Poem: "To a Gentleman" (Box 163, Folder 174)
      - Millicent Todd Bingham's writings about "Visits with Amy" (Box 163, Folder 175)
      - MTB's notes (Box 163, Folder 176)
      - MTB's scrapbook (Box 163, Folder 177)
      - Programs (Box 163, Folder 178)
      - Newspaper clippings (Box 163, Folder 179)
      - Printed matter (Box 163, Folder 180)
    - Lowell, Robert (Box 163, Folder 181)
    - Lunshof, H. A. (Box 164, Folder 182)
    - MacCracken, Henry Noble (Box 164, Folder 183)
    - McHenry, Donald Edward (Box 164, Folder 184)
    - MacLeish, Archibald (Box 164, Folder 185)
    - ________, William H. (Box 164, Folder 185)
    - Meiklejohn, Alexander (Box 164, Folder 186)
    - Meyer, Agnes E. (Box 164, Folder 187)
    - Meyer, Eugene (Box 164, Folder 188)
    - Milinowski, Arthur (Box 164, Folder 189)
    - ________, Carlton (Box 164, Folder 189)
    - Milinowski, Marta (Box 164, Folder 190-194)
    - Miller, Spencer, Jr. (Box 164, Folder 195)
    - Mitchell, Lucy Sprague (Box 164, Folder 196)
    - ________, Wesley Clair (Box 164, Folder 196)
    - Mitchell, William (Box 164, Folder 197)
    - ________, Caroline (Stoddard) (Box 164, Folder 197)
    - Monnier, Mademoiselle Mathilde (Box 164, Folder 198)
    - Munroe, Kirk (Box 164, Folder 199)
    - ________, Mabel (Stearns) Noble (Box 164, Folder 199)
    - Nourse, Anne Constance (Box 164, Folder 200)
    - ________, Charlotte St. George (Box 164, Folder 200)
    - O'Brien, Robert Lincoln (Box 164, Folder 201)
    - Palmer, Alice (Freeman) (Box 164, Folder 202)
    - Palmer, Frederick (Box 164, Folder 203)
    - Palmer, George Herbert
      - Writings of George Herbert Palmer (Box 164, Folder 204)
      - "A Century of English Love Poetry 1575-1675", 1920 (Box 165, Folder 205)
      - Articles and news clippings (Box 165, Folder 206)
      - Scrapbook, notes, typed transcripts of George Herbert Palmer's letters (Box 165, Folder 207)
    - Perkins, Frances (Box 165, Folder 208)
    - Peterson, Roger Tory (Box 165, Folder 209)
    - Pezet, Frederico Alfonso (Box 165, Folder 210)
    - Plimpton, Calvin H. (Box 165, Folder 211)
    - Plimpton, George A. (Box 165, Folder 212)
    - ________, Anne [Fanny Hastings] (Box 165, Folder 212)
    - Porter, Kingsley (Box 165, Folder 213)
    - Porter, Lucius Chapin (Box 165, Folder 214)